(忆往昔)
迪恩
Dean!
莉莎
Lisa.
知道我为什么从不提起我的工作吗
You know how I never mentioned my job?
这就是我的工作
This is my job.
如果不是你  本早就没命了
Ben wouldn't be alive if it wasn't for you.
你可以留下来
You're welcome to stay.
我不能
I can't.
这不是我的生活
It's not my life.
有个人的力量远强于米迦勒
There is someone besides Michael
他能够对付路西法
strong enough to take Lucifer.
-是谁  - 上帝
- Who's that? - God.
我要找出上帝
I'm gonna find god.
我是约书亚
I'm Joshua.
你  能和上帝对话
You...talk to god?
他知道天启被开启了
He knows that the apocalypse has begun.
只不过他认为这跟他没什么关系
He just doesn't think it's his problem.
-跟他没关系  - 他职责已尽
- No his problem? - He's finished.
又一个满嘴借口不负责任的老头  是吗
Just another deadbeat dad with a bunch of excuses, right?
可能约书亚在说谎
Maybe Joshua was lying.
我觉得他没有
I don't think he was.
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
我曾坚信
I believed in...
我们可以找到别的方法
We'll find another way.
我们仍可以阻止这一切  迪恩
We can still stop all this, Dean.
怎么阻止
How?
不知道
I don't know
但我们会找到办法的  你和我
But we'll find it. You and me.
我们会找到的
We'll find it.
(如今)
-再开快点  迪恩  - 已经是极限了
- Drive faster, Dean. - I can't!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
当然  好得不得了
Yeah, I'm amazing.
你以前有见过这么多吗
You ever seen that many?
没  至少一个地方不会有这么多
No. No way. Not in one place.
到底怎么回事
What the hell?
该死的
Damn it!
[咒语]
这情形可不多见啊
Well, that's something you don't see every day.
你们俩没事吧
You two all right?
好得很
Peachy.
留神点儿  这  这儿可是处处危机四伏啊
Be careful. It's...Dangerous around here.
等等  等一下
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait, wait.
不用道谢了
No need to thank us.
不是  稍微等一下  你们是谁
No, hold up a sec! Who are you?
我们是受路德教会洗礼过的自卫队
We're the sacrament Lutheran militia.
抱歉  是什么来着
I'm sorry -- the what?
我也不想告诉你们这些  但那些全是恶魔
I hate to tell you this, but those were demons,
而这一切都源于天启
and this is the apocalypse.
所以  小心点吧
So...Buckle up.
显然我们都是干同一行的
Looks like we're in the same line of business.
没错  都是同行
Yeah, and among colleagues.
那是警用散弹枪吧
That's a police-issue shotgun.
而那个卡车则是
That truck is, uh...
真是太有才了
Inspired.
这些玩意儿你们都是从哪儿搞来的
Where'd you guys pick up all this crap?
这些都是日积月累  水到渠成的
You know, you...Pick things up along the way.
得了  伙计们
Guys, come on.
整个国家都充斥着恶魔出现的征兆
This whole corner of the state is nuts with demon omens.
我们只不过想略尽绵力  仅此而已
We just want to help. That's all.
我们都是同一阵线的
We're on the same team here.
跟我们但说无妨
Just talk to us.
跟我们来
Follow us.
迪伦  这是教堂  把耳机摘了
Dylan, it's a church. Headphones off.
遵命  老妈
Yes, ma'am.
没想到在天启之际还能有如此浪漫之事
Who would have thought the apocalypse could be so romantic?
缔结连理  成立家庭  这是主的恩赐
Marriage, family -- it's a blessing.
尤其是在当下
Especially in times lik this.
所以好好珍惜
So hold on to that.
婚礼啊
Wedding?
没开玩笑吧
Seriously?
没有
Yeah.
到目前为止  这周已有8对新人完婚了
We've had eight so far this week.
罗布说你俩是猎杀恶魔的
So, Rob tells me you boys hunt demons.
是的  神父
Uh...Yes, sir.
那你们错过很多
You missed a few.
没错  谁说不是呢
Yeah, tell us about it.
知道为什么恶魔都聚在这儿吗
Any idea why they're here?
它们肯定是喜欢我们吧
They sure seem to like us, though.
跟我来  先生们
Follow me, gentlemen.
这么说  你是个传教士
So, you're a preacher.
出乎你的意料吗
Not what you expected, huh?
伙计  你可带着枪呢
Well, Dude, you're packing.
非常时期嘛
Strange times.
制盐弹的是个12岁的孩子吗
Is that a 12-year-old packing salt rounds?
每个人都加入进来了
Everybody pitches in.
整个教会吗
So, the whole church?
是整个镇
The whole town.
整个镇全是猎魔人
A whole town full of hunters?
真不知道该尖叫而逃还是该留下安居
I don't know whether to run screaming or buy a condo.
与其被恶魔追杀  还不如奋起反抗
Well, the demons were killing us. We had to do something.
为什么不向其他猎魔人求助呢
So why not call the naional guard?
-有人叫我们别去  - 谁
- We were told not to. - By who?
行了  神父
Come on, Padre.
您都全副武装了还矜持啥
You're as locked and loaded as we've ever seen.
那些驱魔咒都是以诺语
And that exorcism was Enochian.
一定有人教过你什么
Someone's telling you something.
很抱歉  我  我不能透露
Look, I'm sorry. I, uh, I can't discuss it.
-爸爸  没关系  - 莉亚
- Dad, it's okay. - Leah --
他们是温切斯特家的萨姆和迪恩  是自己人
It's Sam and Dean Winchester. They're safe.
我对他们了若指掌
I know all about them.
是吗
You do?
当然
Sure.
从天使那儿了解的
From the angels.
天使那儿  棒极了
The angels. Awesome.
别担心  他们不知道你们在这儿
Don't worry. They can't see you here.
你们肋骨上不是刻有咒文吗
The...Marks on your ribs, right?
那么  我们的事都是天使告诉你的
So, you know all about us because angels told you?
没错  当然还有其他事
Yes. Among other things.
比如那利落的驱魔法术
Like the snappy little exorcism spell.
而且他们还会告诉我恶魔
And they show me where the demons are gonna be
将在哪里现身  我们该如何反击
Before it happens, how to fight back.
她从没出过错  一次也没有
She's never been wrong. Not once.
-她很特别  - 老爸
- She's very special. - Dad.
让我猜猜  在你看见预兆之前
Let me guess -- before you see something,
你头会很痛  还能看见闪光
You get a really bad migraine, you see flashing lights?
你怎么知道的
How'd you know?
你可不是我们遇到的第一个先知
'cause you're not the first prophet we've met.
但你是最迷人的
But you are the cutest.
别误会  我这话完全是出于敬意
I mean that with total respect, of course.
这是语音信箱  请留言给
You've reached the voicemail box of...
我不明白  干嘛要让我说自己的名字
I don't understand. Why do I have to say my name?
卡西  是我
Cass. Hey. Uh, it's me.
我们在明尼苏达的布卢厄斯县
So, we are in blue earth, Minnesota,
我们怕是需要你帮忙了
And, um, we could use a little help.
但愿你能收到
I...Hope you get this.
今晚很忙啊
Busy night.
甭提了  自从末日开启
I'm telling you, since the end started,
这里就没歇过
It's been like one long last call.
-这杯算我的  - 谢谢
- That round's on me. - Thanks.
联系上卡西没
So, did you get ahold of cass?
是的  我给他留了言了
Yeah, I left him a message. I think.
你怎么看
So, uh, what's your theory?
为什么所有恶魔都出动了
Why all the demon hits?
我不清楚
I don't know.
或许是来围杀这先知小姑娘的
Gank the girl prophet, maybe?
-怎么  - 天使们让这些人
- What?  - Just, these angels are sending these people
来做他们的脏活
To do their dirty work.
是啊  那又如何
Yeah. And?
他们都可能死无葬身之地
And they could get ripped to shreds.
我们都会死  萨姆
We're all gonna die, sam,
一个月  或者两个月
In like a month -- maybe two.
我是认真的
I mean it.
这是世界末日啊
I mean, this is the end of the world.
但是这些人没有害怕
But these people aren't freaking out.
事实上  他们在井然有序的奔向终点
In fact, they're running to the exits in an orderly fashion.
我不知道那算不算是一件坏事
I don't know that that's such a bad thing.
谁说他们都会死
Who says they're all gonna die?
那要是我们拯救了他们呢
Whatever happened to us saving them?
如我所言
Something I said?
保罗  怎么了
Paul, what's going on?
莉亚又看到了神示
Leah's had another vision.
要去教堂一趟吗
Want to go to church?
你了解我的  绝对虔诚的信徒
You know me -- downright pious.
距塔尔梅奇路3英里处
3 miles off Talmadge Road.
是5英里
5 miles.
有恶魔聚集
There are demons gathered.
我不知道有多少个  但有很多
I...Don't know how many, but a lot.
谢谢  莉亚
Thank you, Leah.
那么  谁和我一起去
So, who's gonna join me?
到哪都别少了我
Wouldn't miss it.
总得有人罩着罗布
Someone's got to cover Rob's ass.
算上我们  神父
We're in, padre.
谢谢
Thank you.
让我们来祷告
I'd like to offer a prayer.
我们在天上的父
Our father in heaven...
他可没个父亲样儿
Yeah, not so much.
请在我们为你而战时帮助我们
...Please help us in this fight for you.
我们祈求您保护我们不受邪恶之徒伤害
We ask you to protect us form all servants of evil.
指引我们将其击溃
Guide our hands to defeating them.
让我们平安归来
Deliver us home safely.
感激不尽  阿门
Thank you. Amen.
我想这就是那感觉吧
I guess that's what it's like, huh?
什么
What?
有援兵啊
Having backup.
迪恩  萨姆
Dean! Sam!
那个
So, um, is -- is that --
我可以搭你们的车回去吗
Is that cool if I get a ride back with you guys?
你都救了我两次了
Hey, you saved my ass twice already.
再多一次你就可以开我的车了
One more time, you can drive.
要啤酒吗
Get a beer?
你应得的  别跟你妈说
You earned it. Don't tell your mom.
相信我  我不会说的
Oh, believe me -- I will not.
不
No.
夫人  我们非常抱歉
Ma'am, we're just, um, very sorry.
知道吗
You know...
这都怪你们
This is your fault.
简
Jane.
我希望自己知道该说点什么
I wish I knew what to say.
但我不知道
But I don't.
我真的很抱歉  简
I'm so sorry, Jane.
罗布
Rob.
没有预言提到此事
There are no words
迪伦
Dylan...
我不知道这为何会发生
I don't know why this happened.
我不知道这一切都为何会发生
I don't know why any of this is happening.
无从解答
I got no easy answers.
我所知的只是
But what I do know is --
莉亚  莉亚  宝贝
Leah? Leah, honey?
莉亚  宝贝
Leah, honey?
宝贝
Honey?
没事的  亲爱的  没事的
It's okay, sweetie. It's okay.
爸爸  是迪伦
Dad, it's Dylan.
去休息一会吧
Just rest a minute, huh?
不  听着
No, listen.
迪伦会回来的
Dylan's coming back.
简  罗布
Jane, Rob...
一切都会没事的
It's going to be okay.
你们会再见到迪伦的
You'll see Dylan gain.
当末日  也就是审判日到来时
When the final day comes, judgment day,
他会复活的  你们终将团聚
He'll be resurrected, and you'll be together again.
我们都将团聚  和我们所爱的人一起
We'll all be together -- with all our loved ones.
我们是被选中的
We've been chosen.
天使选择了我们
The angels have chosen us.
我们将被赐予人间天堂
And we will be given paradise on earth.
我们需要做的只是遵从天使的诫律
All we have to do is follow the angels' commandments.
戒饮酒  戒赌博  戒婚前性行为
No drinking, no gambling, no premarital sex?
迪恩  基本上这些和你性格的
Dean, they basically just outlawed
90%都格格不入
90% of your personality.
是啊  没办法  入乡随俗吧
Yeah, well, whatever. When in Rome.
这么说  你居然不介意
So, uh... You're cool with it?
我不是不介意  也不是介意
I'm not cool. I'm not not cool. It's --
听着  兄弟  我不是先知
Look, man, I'm not a prophet.
我们不是本地人
We're not locals.
这不是由我决定的
It's not my call.
等会儿再找你
I'll catch up with you.
进来的不是时候吗
This a bad time?
差不多吧
In general.
现在可以了
Now's okay.
天使的事情让你精疲力尽了
Angel stuff really takes it out of you, huh?
没什么好抱怨的
Can't complain.
我知道你经历过更糟糕的
I know you have it worse.
那么  迪恩  你是怎么想的
So...What's on your mind, Dean?
别误会我的意思
Don't take this the wrong way, but...
但是你说的是真的吗
Are you on the level?
哪部分
About what
关于天堂
About paradise.
天堂怎么了
What about it?
我想知道天使们对你说了什么
I want to know what the angels are telling you.
所有的事情
Everything.
"充满希望"那部分就不用说了
And you can skip the rainbows.
会有一场激烈的战斗
There's gonna be a prizefight,
会很惨烈
And... It's gonna get bad.
在我们取胜之后
But after we win --
当然我们会赢的
And we will --
地球将会托付给被选中的人
The planet gets handed over to the chosen,
最终会充满祥和
And... It's finally peaceful.
没有怪物  没有疾病  没有死亡
No monsters, no disease, no death.
人们
You're just...
和相爱的人在一起
With the people you love.
当然  只有当你跨入高级门槛才可以
'Course, that's if you can get past the velvet rope.
被选中肯定很好
Must be nice -- being chosen.
迪恩
Well, Dean...
你就是被选中的
You're chosen.
是
Yeah.
不如说是被诅咒的
More like cursed.
很辛苦吧
Must be hard.
作为天使的皮囊并且不抱希望
Being the vessel of heaven and having no hope.
怎么会这样  不是"天启生意红火"吗
So, what happened to, uh, "The apocalypse is good for business"?
是啊  直到莉亚的天使朋友们禁止了这好事
Oh, yeah. Right up until Leah's angel pals banned the good stuff.
帮我消耗一些库存吧
Help me kill some inventory?
好呀
Sure
别误会
Don't get me wrong.
我在这里长大  我爱这个小镇
I grew up here. I love this town.
但是
But, uh...
那些虔诚的信徒
well, these holy rollers...
是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
我注意到你不是那种会祈祷的人
I, uh, I noticed you're not the praying type.
这是咱的秘密  他们有一半都不是信徒
Yeah, well, between you and me, neither are half those guys.
几个月前  他们都还在这里
Couple of months back, they were all in here,
酗酒  滥交
Getting wasted, banging the nanny.
现在他们都成了上帝的战士了
Now they're all warriors of god.
干杯
Cheers.
听着  恶魔肯定是存在的
Look, there're sure as hell demons.
也许的确有上帝
And maybe there is a god.
我不知道  无所谓  但我不是伪君子
I don't know. Fine. But I'm not a hypocrite.
我之前从未祈祷过  现在也不会开始祈祷
I never prayed before, and I ain't starting now.
如果我下地狱  也是坦坦荡荡的
If I go to hell, I'm going honest.
你呢
How 'bout you?
我什么
What about me?
我猜你也不是一个真正的信徒  对吗
Not a true believer, I take it?
我是信徒  是的
I believe. Yeah.
我是的
I do.
我只是
I'm just...
很确信上帝很久以前就不关心我们了
Pretty sure god stopped caring a long time ago.
你去哪啦
Where you been?
喝酒去了
Drinkin'.
你这个叛徒
You rebel.
我本可以再多喝点的
I'd have had more, um...
但是有宵禁
...But it was curfew.
是的
Right.
你听说他们把信号发射塔关了
You hear they shut down the cell towers?
没有  对我而言这是个新闻
No. That's, uh, news to me
是呀
Yeah.
没有有线电视和网络
No cable, internet.
与"外面腐朽的世界"完全隔离
Total cutoff from the "Corruption of the outside world."
你还不懂吗
Don't you get it?
他们在把这个地方变为
They're turning this place
类似于正统基督教聚集的地方
Into some kind of fundamentalist compound.
是的  我懂
No, I get it.
那你就只会哼一声
And all you got's a "Hmm"?
你怎么了
What's wrong with you?
我懂  我只是不关心
I get it. I just don't care.
什么
What?
有什么区别吗
What difference does it make?
区别大了去了
It makes a hell of a --
从啥时起这事与你无关了
At what point does this become too far for you?
石箭  毒圣水[指信徒之虔诚]
Stoning? Poisoned kool-aid?
天使们在耍这些人
The angels are toying with these people.
天使的世界要守他们的规矩  伙计
Angel world, angel rules, man.
什么时候开始你对此无动于衷了
And since when is that okay with you?
从天使们成了唯一的希望开始
Since the angels got the only lifeboats on the titanic.
我是说  到底谁应该
I mean, who exactly is
现身去拯救这些人
supposed to come along and save these people?
曾经应该是我们
It was supposed to be us.
我们不行
We can't do it.
那么  你想
So, what, you -- you want to --
不再战斗  自暴自弃
You want to just stop fighting, roll over?
我不知道  也许吧
I don't know. Maybe.
别那样说
Don't say that.
-为什么呢  - 你不能这样
- Why not?  - 'Cause you can't do this.
实际上  我可以
Actually, I can.
不  你不能  你不能这样对我
No, you can't. You can' this to me.
我有一股力量支撑着自己
I got one thing -- one thing keeping me going.
你以为只有你在挣扎吗  迪恩
You think you're the only one white-knuckling it here, Dean?
我没法依靠别人了
I can't count on anyone else.
我也没法一个人完成
And I can't do this alone.
迪恩
Dean.
我要静一静
I got to clear my head.
现在是宵禁时间
It's past curfew.
已经过宵禁了
莉亚  出什么事了
Leah. What's wrong?
爸爸  我能跟你谈谈吗
Daddy, can I alk to you for a second?
当然了
Of course.
莉亚  亲爱的  怎么了
Leah, honey, w-wha is it?
对不起  我很抱歉  他们都很生气
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. They're just so angry.
-谁很生气  - 那些天使
- Who's angry?  - The angels.
他们为什么生气呢
Why are they angry?
他们说
They said...
他们说  我们不能去天堂
they said that we can't go to paradise.
什么
What.
但他们说的每一件事我们都做了
But we're doing everything they say!
他们声称  他们下达了明确的命令
They said they gave clear commandments,
但是我们之中有人没有服从
but some people aren't listening.
是谁  莉亚
Who, Leah?
我收到了你的留言
I got your message.
你的留言  真长
It was long, your message.
你的声音听起来有些刺耳
And I find the sound of your voice grating.
你怎么了
What's wrong with you?
你是不是
Are you...
喝高了
drunk?
没有
No!
是的
Yes.
你到底怎么了
What the hell hppened to you?
我找到一家酒品店
I found a liquor store.
然后呢
And?
然后我喝了个痛快
And I drank it.
你找我干嘛
Why'd you call me?
哇  稳住  小心点
whoa. There you go. Easy.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
别问这么蠢的问题
Don't ask stupid questions.
找我到底什么事
Tell me what you need.
这里一直频繁遭到恶魔袭击
T-there have been these -- these demon attacks,
就在镇子周围
massive, right on the edge of town,
我们搞不懂为什么他们...
and we can't figure out why they're --
有天使出现的迹象吗
Any sign of angels?
算是吧
Sort of.
他们一直在和这个先知交流
They've been speaking to this prophet.
哪个先知
Who?
是个女孩  叫莉亚·吉迪恩
This girl, Leah Gideon.
她不是先知
She's not a prophet.
我很确定她是
I'm pretty sure she is.
幻象  头疼  该有的征兆她都有
Visions, headaches -- the whole package.
所有先知的名字
The names of all the prophets --
都深深刻在我脑子里
they're seared into my brain.
莉亚·吉迪恩不是其中之一
Leah Gideon is not one of them.
那她是什么
Then what is she?
我告诉过你
I told you...
大家都镇静
Please guys guys!
我不需要再跟你说第二遍
I don't need to tell you again.
你们俩  都别激动
Take a breath, both of you!
你们跑到我的地盘  出言不逊
You come on my property, spouting some kind of crazy --
抱歉保罗  我们别无选择
Sorry, Paul! There's no other way!
拜托  这是个什么地方
Come on! What country is this, huh?
神父  要帮忙吗
Need a hand, Padre?
大家都先冷静一下
Just, everybody cool down for a minute!
冷静是吗
"Cool down," Eh?
我兄弟想把我扫地出门  赶出这个镇
My friends are trying to run me out of town.
你觉得我该冷静吗
Do you think I should cool down?
保罗我很抱歉  这不是我们能决定的
I'm sorry, Paul. It is not our choice.
拜托  别扯淡了
Oh, come on. That's bull.
为了大家  你必须走
You got to go -- for everyone's sake!
我们从小一起长大
We grew up together.
我出席了你的婚礼
I stood up at your wedding!
是啊  确实  不过那是过去
Yes, you did, but that was then.
而现在  你站在民众的对立面了
And now you're standing against the flock.
这不是事实  我和你们并肩战斗的
That's not true. I fight with you.
保罗  这个镇子的人都是信徒
This is a town of believers, Paul.
而你不是
You are not a believer.
别让我们为难了
Don't make this hard for us.
让你为难
Hard for you?
不
No.
这是我的家
This is my home.
你们想让我走人
You want me out of here?
那就得先放倒我
You'll have to drag me out.
嘿  你可不想这么做
Whoa, whoa, whoa. You don't want to do this.
滚开
Get out of my --
别  停手
No, no, no.
谁都不能阻止我再见到我儿子
No one's gonna stop me from seeing my son again.
我们到处找你
We went out looking for --
你没事吧
You all right?
没事  这不是我的血
Yeah. It's -- it's not my blood.
保罗死了
Paul's dead.
啥
What?!
简一枪嘣了他
Jane shot him.
开始了
It's starting.
什么开始了
What's starting?
你他妹的跑哪去了
Where the hell have you been?
寻欢作乐
On a bender.
他  你刚是说寻欢作乐吗
Did he -- did you say "On a bender"?
是啊  他现在还没缓过来呢
Yeah. He's still pretty smashed.
这个不重要
It is not of import.
我们得谈谈这里发生的事
We need to talk about what's happening here.
洗耳恭听
Well, I'm all ears.
好吧  首先
Well, for starters...
莉亚不是先知
Leah is not a real prophet.
那她到底是啥
Well, what is she, exactly?
淫妇
The Whore.
卡西  说说你到底是怎么想的
Wow. Cass, tell us what you really think.
路西法再临人间的时候  她也复活了
She rises when Lucifer walks the earth.
"她将降临  传播错误的预言"
"And she shall come, bearing false prophecy."
这东西能化作人形
This creature has power to take a human's form,
还会读心术
read minds.
启示录称她为  巴比伦淫妇
Book of Revelation calls her "The Whore of Babylon."
够醒目的
Well, that's catchy.
真正的莉亚可能好几个月前就被杀了
The real Leah was probably killed months ago.
那恶魔袭击镇子怎么解释呢
What about the demons attacking the town?
它们都听她指挥
They're under her control.
那些驱魔咒呢
And the Enochian exorcism?
假的
Fake.
它们真正的意思是
It actually means
"你个山羊嘴里吐出来的"
"You, um, breed with the mouth of a goat."
还是用以诺语说比较好玩
It's funnier in Enochian.
那些恶魔化烟而飞  其实都是假的了
So the demons smoking out -- that's just a con?
为什么  它们有什么目的啊
Why? What's the endgame?
你刚刚亲眼所见的
What you just saw --
以上帝的名义让无辜百姓鲜血四溅
Innocent bloods spilled in god's name.
那些所谓神谕你都听见了
You all heard that heaven talk.
她操纵利用人们
She manipulates people.
让人们一边唱着赞美诗一边肆意杀戮
To slaughter and kill and sing peppy little hymns.
太厉害了
Awesome.
她的目的就是尽量把人们的灵魂送往地狱
Her goal is to condemn as many souls to hell as possible.
这才只是刚开始
And it's...Just beginning.
用不了多久
She's well on her way
她就能让整个镇子都万劫不复了
to dragging this whole town into the pit.
好吧
All right.
我们要怎么解决那个来自巴比伦的
So, then, how do we go pimp of Babylon
拉皮条的贱人
all over this bitch?
我只是想...
I only wanted to --
我把事情变得更糟了吗
Did I make it worse?
我惹怒了天使们吗
Did I make the angels angry?
简
Jane.
天使们  他们理解的
The angels -- they understand.
你所做的是为了大局着想
What you did is for the greater good.
是啊
Yes.
太好了
我们都喜欢保罗
We all liked Paul.
但他是个罪人
But he was a sinner,
他会连累我们同他一起下地狱的
and he would have taken us down with him.
你拯救了我们
You saved us.
谢谢
Thank you.
这怎么可能没事呢
How can that be okay?
她杀了保罗
She killed him.
这项罪孽可远大于...
That sin is so much greater--
打败邪恶之人可不是罪孽
It's not a sin to strike down evil.
但是那些天使怎么会
But how can the angels --
你总是教导我要怀有信仰
You always taught me that we have to have faith.
用这个可以杀了淫妇
The whore can be killed with that.
这是由生长在巴比伦的柏树制成的树桩
It's a stake made from a cypress tree in babylon.
很好  我们去消灭她吧
Great. Let's ventilate her.
可没那么简单
It's not that easy.
当然了
Of course not.
只有真正的天主之仆才能杀死淫妇
The whore can only be killed by a true servant of heaven.
-仆人  就像...  - 你不行
- Servant, like... - Not you.
我也不行
Or me.
当然  主肯定是恨死萨姆了
Sam, of course, is an abomination.
我们必须找别人来干这事
We'll have to find someone else.
天使们
The angels...
我也不清楚他们为什么选中了我们
I don't know why they've chosen us.
不过事实如此
But they have.
今天
And today...
就在今天  他们告知了我最重要的事情
Today, they told me the most important thing yet.
今晚子夜
Tonight, at midnight...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
只是  我们都清楚这天总会到来
It's just that we knew this day would come,
现在它就要实现了
and it's here --
最后的审判
The final judgment.
现在  我们要立刻行动
Now, we need to do this right.
没有多少时间了
We don't have much time.
天使们认为我们还没做好准备
The angels said we're not ready.
还有一些事情需要我们去解决
There are still a few elements that need to be taken care of.
罪人
Sinners.
好了  大家都冷静下
Now, uh, now, everybody calm down.
先等等
Just hold on.
莉亚  你吓到大家了
Leah, you're scaring these people.
我并不是要让大家恐慌  但我们必须抓紧了
Now, I don't want us to panic, but we have to hurry.
停下来
Stop it.
我已经接到了指令和名单
I've been given instructions, names.
等一下
Wait.
你到底在干什么啊  快停下
What are you doing? Stop it!
你这样会害死人的
You're gonna get somebody killed.
放开我
Let me go.
否则下一个被我指出的罪人就会是你
Or the next sinner I name will be you.
你是戴维·吉迪恩牧师
Pastor David Gideon?
是啊  你是哪位
Yeah. Who are you?
我是天主的使臣
I'm an angel of the lord.
是嘛  天使啊
Yeah, sure.
这算哪门子事儿
What the hell was that?
他的确是个天使
Yeah, he wasn't lying about the angel thing.
请坐吧  神父  我们需要谈谈
Have a seat, padre. We got to have a chat.
不行
No.
她可是我的女儿啊
She's my daughter.
很抱歉  但她不是
I'm sorry, but she's not.
是她杀了你的女儿
She's the thing that killed your daughter.
这不可能的啊
That's impossible.
千真万确
But it's true.
你心里也很清楚
And deep down, you know it.
我们理解  这要求很过分
Look, we get it -- it's too much.
但是如果你选择退缩
But if you don't do this,
她会害死更多人
she's going to kill a lot of people
而剩下的人会下地狱
and damn the rest to hell.
只是...
It's just...
为什么单单选我去干这事呢
Why does it have to be me?
你是天主之仆
You're a servant of heaven.
你还是天使呢
And you're an angel.
并不算是
Poor example of one.
注意
Heads up.
我该吃多少
How many should I take?
你吗
You?
你还是把整瓶都吃了吧
You should probably just down the whole bottle.
谢了
Thanks.
客气什么
Yeah, don't mention it.
我是过来人
Yeah, I've been there.
我可是对付不负责任的老爹的专家
I'm a big expert on deadbeat dads,
所以
So...
我明白的
Yeah, I get it.
我能体会你的感觉
I know how you feel.
你是怎么解决的呢
How do you manage it?
如此美好的一天  斩妖除魔才是王道
On a good day, you get to kill a whore.
罗布  简  求求你们
Rob, Jane, please!
求你们了  是我啊  伊莉斯
Come on, it's me! It's Elise!
真的很抱歉
Sorry. Really.
但你明白我们必须那么做
But you know we have to do this.
把他们关到储藏室
We're putting them in the storage unit.
不要  不要
No! No!
简  人齐了吗
Jane, is that everyone?
好吧
Okay, then.
去拿煤油
Get the kerosene.
怎么了
What?
那里面还有孩子呢
There are kids in there.
天使们指名他们一定是有原因的
The angels named them for a reason.
简
Jane...
你儿子需要你这么做
Your son needs you to do this.
爸爸  别伤害我
Daddy! Don't hurt me!
吉迪恩  快
Gideon, now!
吉迪恩
Gideon!
等等  别
Wait! No!
救命  他是个恶魔
Help me! He's a demon!
去点火
Light the kerosene.
快快
come on come on.
省省吧  你是天主之仆么
Please. Like you're a servant of heaven.
放开我
Let me go!
所以我们才会赢
This is why my team's gonna win.
你是那重要的皮囊
You're the great vessel?
我看你可怜  自我憎恨  还毫无信仰
You're pathetic, self-hating, and faithless.
世界末日到了
It's the end of the world.
你只能袖手旁观  看着一切发生
And you're just gonna sit back and watch it happen.
别说得那么肯定  淫妇
Don't be so sure, whore.
但我  我不明白
But I... I don't understand.
现在我们该怎么去天堂
How are we supposed to get to paradise now?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
天堂你们肯定是去不成了
Pretty sure you're headed in a different direction.
没事了
Gotcha.
来
Come on.
迪恩  你怎么办到的
Dean, how did you do that?
什么
What?
杀掉她
Kill her.
人品爆发了吧  我猜
Long run of luck held out, I guess.
据我所知  她只会被
Last I checked, she could only be ganked
天主之仆所伤
by a servant of heaven.
你想听我说什么
Well, what do you want me to tell you?
我只是把握住机会而已
I saw a shot. I went for it.
好了
Here we go.
小心头
Watch your head, now.
你是要做什么蠢事么
Are you gonna do something stupid?
比如说
Like what?
比如米迦勒版迪恩那种
Like Michael stupid.
行了吧萨姆  饶了我吧
Come on, Sam. Give me a break.
你头怎么样了
How's the head?
我看东西双影了
I'm seeing double.
也许是止疼药的作用
But that may be the painkillers.
你会没事的
You'll be okay.
不
No.
你去哪儿
Where you going?
去车里找些干净的绷带  别紧张
I'm just gonna grab some clean bandages out of the trunk.Relax.
好了  怎么样
OK over there. How was that...
该死的  迪恩
Damn it! Dean!
迪恩
Dean.
嗨  莉莎
Hi, Lisa.
我没有你的电话号码  所以
I didn't have your number, uh, so...
不不  没关系
No. No, it's okay.
我  我只是很惊讶
I'm -- I'm...Just surprised.
本怎么样
How's Ben?
很好
Good.
很好  他打棒球去了
Good. He's at baseball.
真是
That's, uh...
你搬家了
You moved.
这  房子不错
It's a...nice house.
迪恩  你跑这么远过来
Dean, you didn't come all the way here
不是要说房子什么的吧
to talk about real estate.
你还好吧
You all right?
不  不太好
No, not really.
怎么了
What is it?
听着  我没出现幻觉
Look, I have no illusions, okay?
我知道我的生活是如何的
I know the life that I live,
也知道一切将怎样结束
I know how that's gonna end for me.
不管怎样  我都无所谓了
Whatever. I'm okay with that.
但我想让你知道
But I wanted you to know...
我脑中浮现的最快乐的时光
...That when I do picture myself happy...
是和你
...It's with you.
还有孩子在一起
and the kid.
你什么也不用说
I mean, you don't have to say anything.
不  我是说  我知道我不用说什么
No, I... I mean, I know. I know.
可我想和你聊
I want to.
进来吧  来喝一杯
Come inside. Let me get you a beer.
我也想
I wish I could.
自己保重  莉莎
Take care of yourself, lisa.
别  等等
No. No, wait, wait.
你不能突然来了吓我一通又马上走
You can't just drop a bombshell like that and then leave.
我知道
I know.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
但我别无选择
But I don't have a choice.
不  你有  你有的
Yeah, you do. You do.
你可以进来让我倒杯酒给你  咱们聊聊
You can come inside and let me get you a beer. We can talk.
莉莎  等等
Lisa, wait a minute.
情况真的会很糟
Things are about to get really bad.
举个例子呢
Like how?
-像你这样子吗  - 更糟
- Like your kind of bad? - Worse.
接下来的几天  你会从电视上看到的一些
Next few days, the crap you're gonna see on your tv,
相当诡异的东西
it' s gonna be downright trippy.
很可怕
Scary.
但我不想让你担心
But I don't want you to worry,
因为我会安顿好你和本
because I'm making arrangements for you and ben.
安顿
Arrangements?
不管发生什么  你们都不会有事
Whatever happens, you're gonna be okay.
你什么意思  你说什么呢
What do you mean? What are you talking about?
我要去见的人
The people that I'm gonna see next,
除非他们同意我开出的一些条件
they're not gonna get anything from me
否则别想从我这捞到什么
without agreeing to a few conditions.
进来说吧  求你
Just...Just come inside. Please.
不管你打算干什么  别去
And whatever you're thinking of doing, don't do it.
我必须去
I have to.
只是陪我一个小时
Just stay an hour.
至少要和本说再见
At least say bye to Ben.
还是不说的好
Ah, it's better if I don't.
再见  莉莎
Bye, Lisa.